[Music]
it's a beautiful day in this
neighborhood the beautiful day for a
neighbor would you be fine
what you be my neighbor lead a in this
beauty would the neighborly thing would
you be mine could you be mine
I have always wanted to have a neighbor
just like you
I've always wanted to live in the
neighborhood
with you so let's make the most of this
beautiful day since we're together might
as well say when you be mine could you
be mine won't you be my neighbor
simply long sleeve please won't you be
my neighbor neighbor you see that big
suitcase that I brought with me
well it doesn't have suits in it no I'm
not going on a trip as something else
very special in there remember yesterday
we were talking about things on
television that were just pretend
well i was talking with the young friend
of mine who said you know something that
I think's pretend the neighborhood of
make-believe and of course my young
friend was right
many of the characters in the
neighborhood of make-believe are puppets
that I make talk i'll show you as that's
what's in here
puppets that I make talk and sometimes
use this little bag to carry them and I
always have soft material so that he'll
be well taken care of
here's a puppet that lives in a little
schoolhouse in a tree and really put the
kit very beautiful miao and we have
immunity
and here is an owl who is her neighbor
all name is X the owl Henrietta me out
there are two of the puppets
here's someone who is the curator of the
museum go round
hello friends my name's lady lane
Fairchild and you're someone who
manufactures rocking chairs
I'm a man who manufactures and now cord
like a specially
and here are some people who live in a
castle
how do you do it is the gentleman
how do you do would you take a close
look at King Friday the thirteenth and
pretend that you have a puppet on your
hand and just have your puppets say
something to the king have your puppet
tell him something
yeah o2w to know was it a scary thing
that your puppet told the king or a
happy thing or a sad thing to see
puppets can talk about anything here is
the Queen Queen Sara well how do you do
friday how do you do
Queen their own idea
so you can make the kids there's Prince
Tuesday
compare module amazed at me baby seat SQ
and who lives in the clock in your
striper Tigers my name I and somebody
who always sings what he says I'm happy
to be here today under my friend and the
donkey lives at someplace else
uh-huh all their friends know a
filmmaker made a movie of me behind the
castle with the king and queen on my
hands one day when we were working on
the neighborhood of make-believe and I'd
like you to see that film you'll also
see my friend mr. Barker who makes the
Platypus puppets talk
there
let's take a look at that film taken in
the neighborhood of make-believe as we
were working
[Music]
I put on the king and the Queen
and then put them through and make the
more cap from the castle
[Music]
and then I walked over to see the
platypuses I'll see gene and dr. Bell
[Music]
there's my friend mr. Barker we've been
good friends for many years and that's
the way we usually greet each other with
that handshake salute
now there's one other puppet Harriet
Elizabeth cow can you imagine who makes
her voice
one of my neighbors in this neighborhood
let's go over where that NeighborWorks
I'd like you to see who it is i'll take
Harriet Elizabeth cow and Don Quixote in
this bag you guess I'm with me
i bought bread I'll be right with you
soon as I get this is hose clamp on here
what are you doing I'm preparing a
washer/dryer just one machine one
machine
I mean it does both the washing and
drying inside here
that's right hot water goes in there and
cold water goes in these clamps are
sometimes very hard to get on when i was
little i thought that washing machines
and drying machines that were kind of
magic to know magic about them it's just
a machine grid is 1 second rewrite up
it's so nice to be able to just put your
dirty clothes sheets and pillowcases in
that little door over there and push one
of these dials and have it all happened
washes to spin dries them and rinses and
invest it
what would Harry in this house today
about that Harriet cow is it really you
I'll say it was really good ride
well I say it may be a surprise for some
of my friends I wanted them to know who
did the voices of the different puppets
you know who made them targets a good
idea
e are Harriet cow donkey holding your
I'm just great good
what's this down here that's a washer
dryer washer dryer
what about washer dryers order dumper
washer/dryer sort of dumper it's even
how to say isn't it well that's right
but you know we use it in someplace else
that we do and it started right here
right here right Bob
that's it that's correct right start
right over here i want okay i want to
show them the washer/dryer shorter
dumper to find you see you
this is the Machine and people have to
work it underneath here see you know how
the potato goes along like that and then
goes up to the washer so forth the
potato and will actually do it you have
one we could try bc the washer/dryer
sorter dumper it dumps it right into the
potato train over there we set all this
up to make some place else have 10 good
litigator I'd test it because it needed
some repairs and I don't know whether
it's gonna work all right or not but
we'll try it it's okay comes along like
it slowly carefully i get up a great
position ready okay i bring along here
and hang up to get it with a little help
it's very hard to make again I'll see
what I can do with that dropping it up
one up even do it up about the right
like it out there and you can dump it
out
ok any google know
yep there you go with down haha we
shouldn't play with food like that but
there sure
ok their potato well thank you baba i
just wanted to show my friends some of
the things about television that just
weren't real
I think that's important thing to show
you know some of those scary cartoons &
things
sure just made out of pictures and stuff
I know show them all the other couples
you know voices some think we will see
you later Harriet and Don Quixote ok pop
off assay later bye
[Music]
and you guessed it was Bob stress does
the voice for hairless with cap i'll say
you like to say i'll say here's a
picture here i'd like you to see who do
you think plays the part of Bob dog in
the neighborhood of make-believe
remember yesterday we pretended that
Francois Clemens was taking pictures at
the fancy dress party
well suppose he and Bob dog are together
now they could go and visit Lady Elaine
to a little bit but they could be
together right now as the trolley comes
by the castle in the neighborhood of
make-believe show you the Pixies okay
haha like that king and queen right and
then I took one of you and me yet
rule the world where is everybody
that's right then we all get together 21
tell you what why don't I take one of
you right now Bob dog
ye-yeah oh are you understand what about
just staying right here and now come
over here you want me smile
yeah why don't you give me a nice big
smile hold still now I've got there ok
want to see ya i like to see it
ok you like that yeah that's alright
with teeth you know some people are
afraid of my teeth even when i'm smiling
oh yeah well I wanna take another
picture of you with your lips covering
your teeth that's a good idea
okay what do you want to stand this time
well I'll just sort of ok then I'll
scoot over here I whole still again
that's nice
there we go bottom mhm okay you like
that that's funny one isn't that uh huh
but teeth are showing that's good that's
the case here whenever I can't one of
you what look i'm going to show you
something first I'd like them together
what I like kinda like them both
you like them both but what really like
is to take one of you ok alright tell
this works okay first of all you look
through here
that's right and then you have to push
this button ok and then you pull the
picture out right all right okay I'm
gonna stand over there and put my cat
camera case there it just back worn off
that's far enough and be sure to hold
the camera steady I will okay yeah not i
love working here sa and I push for just
buy ads right okay here your growth you
hold a to ok that's where is that you
pull it pull it out right here
go yeah that's nice that's a nice
picture
wait a minute who's out in the
background but that's Lady Elaine
Fairchild yeah there's years of the
bottom museums around let's go show our
pictures
okay I'll get my case finally land
hello sweets how are things with this
fine
we'd like to show you some of the
pictures i've been taking his blood well
i have exactly eight seconds to spare
well then I'll hurry hmm yeah real my
this museum go round of minus okay ready
yeah sure
all right who's that that's you that's a
very pleasant person in the background
and was that that is Bob dog showing his
teeth is right and what is another one
was that bob-dog not showing his teeth
that's right now I have time for one
more that's want one I want to show you
one special which is one more move that
all that lady elaine fairchilde
yesterday trade with the party dress on
wasn't a nice party
yes but i still think a wedding would
have been nicer but now i'm interested
in something else
and what's that about then what does
that stand for MGR my great room and
museum go round of course now take that
brush
ok what you want me to do with it stick
it in the paint and add two letters to
my sign here o.o what two letters lame
TV of course TV m xi r T V MGR TV
museum go around television
I'm starting my own television station
you're starting your own TV station
right here
you heard it huh you're always
television station going home yeah come
on now come on inside now show you my
studio
I'm expecting some more equipment to
arrive any minute now that sounds
exciting come on now there's a
stepladder and some of the lights in the
microphone boom huh
and you think buddy let this this place
is fantastic and of course right over
here you see where we'll do the
interview shows
uh-huh I mean when the TV camera comes
you can work if you want to
I've always wanted to work a TV camera
sure just put yours right now okay
hey that maybe it's coming now delivery
what I mean your camera is coming by air
sure you know she's bringing it all
their name
hi-yah is this what you really ordered
that's that that's exactly what I want
Josh to what do you think of this place
I don't believe it I think it's great
television studio tell me we're cleaning
well of course up France why don't you
work the camera
ok Yoshi you work the microphone and
I'll just interview you Bob dog you just
sit right over here and that yeah we'll
just get a little program right here
you're not okay let me just test the
software that's good yeah okay to work
ok yeah look at this one are you doing
you just let down that everybody has
that that's it that's a little closer to
her and medicines management interview
it should be that's right ok you set
friend was just as I'm focusing yeah
yeah but you said yes yes i think so
ok big band ready for testing one
[Music]
I sweets this is your charming hostess
lady elaine fairchilde bringing you the
best of MGR TV and now today our guest
here at MGR TV is that talented Bob dog
[Music]
sorry
yeah what do you like to do bob i like i
like to be on television
good and what do you like to do on
television
well I always always always wanted to
always want to dance the dance well go
right ahead
we like our guests to feel right at home
let's have a big hand for Bobby doggy
and his dancing pause
[Applause]
[Music]
what
wow yeah that was really great
you want to work the camera what like
that okay
france yes let's bob-dog work the camera
okay now everyone out there in
television land that bob-dog is going to
work the camera and the two singers of
the century
ito and Clemens are going to sing for us
whoa whoa whoa that's what was different
ok ok you thinking what I'm doing
pretending pretending
I'll start okay three tending your pilot
or a Prince's pretending you're a doctor
or a key pretending your mother died
free 10 you can be
to thank 53 10
just written you can try out many by
your own work of play can be different
every day but it's your you can try the
library
[Music]
we
let's hear it for them
well now thank you friends this is your
neighborhood television station MGR Lady
Elaine is going to have her own
television station which puppets do you
think would like to make up a television
show of their own
I'm not so sure I'd be able to well
Edgar could always try if you're
interested maybe I could talk about
clocks and loving Who and things like
that
sure Daniel whatever you'd like to do to
make up a television program
y-you potential shot they all off on the
not Barkley besides of course from there
that would be up to you
each person makes up what he or she
would like to make up i would give long
speeches on television I would say that
if it were not for me there would be no
television i am the key kind of program
do you think the Queen Sara might like
to make up something about children
something about her work with plants her
work with the microscope
what about cornflake especially when I
could you show everybody had to make
rocking chairs if they wanted to learn
hey that's my business and i love it
with me to shine me out that would be up
to you Henrietta
I think you'd be just great young reader
i might even like tell people how to fly
a lion with xo-1 beautiful mio mio
that's serious business
those puppets
that's part of my business
you know I have that kind of business
because I care about you
people like you make up television
programs for children and their families
it's such a good feeling to know you're
alive it's such a happy feeling you're
growing inside and when you wake up
ready to say I think I'll make us
napping new day it's such a good feeling
very good feeling feeling you know
that i'll be back when the day is new
and I'll never more ideas for you and
you'll have things you want to talk
about i will to you always make it a
special day for me I like you just the
way you are helping back tomorrow bye
[Music]
the people who gave the money to make
this television visit by the people of
the sears roebuck foundation and the
Corporation for Public Broadcasting
this is PBS