[Music]
it's a beautiful day in this
neighborhood a beautiful day for a
neighbor would you be mine could you be
mine
it's a neighborly day in this BTW word
neighborly j4 beauty would you be mine
could you be mine
I have always wanted to have a neighbor
like you always wanted to live in the
name her foot with you so let's make the
most of this beautiful there since we're
together we might as well say would you
be mine could you be mine I want to be
my neighbor you please please won't you
be my neighbor and we are neighbors
aren't we
we're television neighbors yes i will
show you something
this is an invitation that is my first
name it says fret ffred the invitation
says you are invited to Joan agrees
music shop and inside it says that were
invited to come over to join a group
music shop to have a free musical lesson
a musical lesson of our choice
well we'll do that in just a little bit
i want to show you something
no I showed you that that was my first
name fret and some people call me mr.
Rogers but some people call me Fred
yeah this says the a
d that says that my son's call me Dad
will print this and see if you know what
that is
does that look like this one
they both say Fred now I wonder if you
know what this says that says milk and
so it is that I must put the milk in the
refrigerator before we go
[Music]
I think maybe I'll see you in a little
while fish think maybe I'd like to have
a drum lesson
yeah always wanted to learn to play the
drums
let's go to the Greek music shop you
know I like to learn new things come
along
[Music]
what people look at all the things going
on here
yeah I read how are you nice to see you
too busy here
yeah I can be tempting you're on set how
do you do mr. Robinson she's interested
in the guitar and I think she's doing
very well with for her first lesson if
you have your lesson
good i said you feel free to look around
the store maybe there's something else
you'd like to try with some problems
over differently
alright you read what you will interest
you and what did you draw i'd like to
learn the drivers yourself you would yes
I've always wanted to know more about
them and I'd like to learn some fancy
things on school principal be rushing
right left right left right yeah I
that's very with no that's called his
paradiddle figures seem so very good
exercise to practice this morning and
right Superman and wrong and breakfast
bad practice pad and a set of sticks can
be purchased right over the counter
thank thank you very much right on
ladies thanks Bob well thank you for
coming by to get by
well well well Johan all right round
afraid you
nice to see you thank you thank you
talking about the ground alright if you
give me a lesson
fine right here not thank you
now this is a practice pic never seen a
little one like this this is a drum
uranus in the drum this is not a drop
this is a practice pad that we use this
to practice this is the crimp this is a
lot offered drama huh
so we're going to start with the
practice band alright i think the first
thing we should do before we use the
sticks for the drum or the practice pad
is play with our fingers see if we can
do two single strokes is on the side of
the practice pan right left
this is something you could do what you
can do this at home one table top box
and turned upside down
now try double strokes to with each
finger right right left left right
you didn't try that huh alright alright
alright good now let's try with stickers
a pair of sticks would be pretty good
for you let's have your right hand first
I just told that stick about there and
close your hand over like you would a
hammer a screwdriver to turn over and
try for a couple strokes that's good
right now see this is a lot louder you
can see why we use a practice right now
the left hand palm of your hand up stick
there between these two fingers and sort
of curl your fingers around your thumb
on top that's it
good try someone just the left and just
like that yes that's good alright i'll
try the single strokes with the sticks
good now how about the double strokes
good now we're going to try something is
a combination of the single and a double
it's called a paradiddle paradiddle is
an exercise called a paradiddle but you
were teaching that one before
yes that's right yes uh-huh i'll try
that that's right left right right right
left right right not tried starting with
the left hand right left right left
right right you can play this and say it
at the same time it's fun to play and
it's fun to say ok red dead don't air it
did yes
with your fingers era era did when
you're playing at home you don't have to
stick to these exercises
it's just sort of play along to the
music on the radio or the record player
you mean just sort of way along and make
it fun but these are certain exercises
you can use a stick to that's right
that's good
there's one other exercise would be fun
called a random q random q Adamek you
yea rather make you can just a random q
paradiddle and random q two things we
learn i'll show you the random that is
that gets a random cute
it's a random acute it's a random
grabbing the queue it's over with you
its name is really what's in your box
mr. Bailey and trying to find out what
we have but it's a battle McHugh it's
rather like you rather than as you
practices you'll get a little bit faster
and it was signed up to hear that drama
with Sonic
well you have to practice a long time
for that yes you certainly do but you
know I wonder how I could get one of
these
well that could work you can buy a
practice pad an affair sticks right over
there by one yes I practice but yes so
you have a single strokes that double
strokes paradiddle and Brad okay thank
you very much your good teacher operate
well thank you how goes it them all
right and arrange for less than some
very good thanks so much my friend by AJ
it's your rising I'd like to buy a
practice pad and sticks alright alright
drum I just was learning will get the
drums there that's yeah there's lots to
work on the good luck at seven dollars
that's just right there
okay thank you very much thank you but I
practice on a half hour with it
well red one yeah fine had molested
self-help yeah
David are you mr. our clip learning
paradiddles and random accused you do
that on the guitar
no can't do whether the kids a burner
just G chord these over the right that's
enough for doing very good and come back
so see you next weekend alright thank
you get it by David we had a good time
did you really yeah it's very good
teacher would you like to see more time
practicing is going on in that back room
is that a musical instrument mr. McFeely
head I'm not gonna tell you learn that
let's take a look
so that what it is that's what was in
the Box a typewriter a typewriter
oh right I mr. feel it yeah but you're
practicing would you like to see you
some exercises yeah right i love it
one of his a sdf-1 a gay al and
semicolon there you go whenever just the
right fingers for you one just the right
ones would like to see your name i would
already capital F red2 good for you mr.
you know there's my name on the
invitation
does that name look the same as this one
to you if so you're learning to read
what about the walkie-talkie mr. McCall
you wanna try that
no I didn't bite i decided not to get it
I don't mind going home and pick up my
messages
it gives me exercise that gives me a
chance to visit with Betsy yeah well we
have a good time is another 1i could
write AI didn't know you'd be here we
thought we'd go to play a little while
I'm practicing my typewriter and I'm
learning the drum
oh hey would you want to have some fun
with us already
why don't we do a thing together with
that the typewriter up doesn't take away
from your time you're over here to join
in with the guitar since these are such
fancy instruments why would Aaron it's
okay everybody all right here we go
[Music]
really was great thanks for the add on
y'all can get to work next time I try
less alone there is a good idea i mean
take care later I Johnny down a piece of
paper and all the practice with cream is
really about
I'm sorry still learning to put to play
the typewriter
well I sure hope that all of this is
helping your business
it certainly is i'm waters for
instruments in for lessons and a couple
of special surprises coming up later for
you
they say you later bye hi
always
[Music]
can hardly wait to get here to try this
again that's fun practicing paradiddle
and random q i think i'd like to feed
the fish and then after that have some
make-believe they're hungry
ok ready for some make-believe let's get
the trolley the trolley school bus this
[Music]
okay Charlie let's think now wonder how
Daniel Tiger's feeling about starting
school maybe lady aberlin could be
taking something for him to eat or to
drink in the neighborhood of
make-believe let's have them visit for a
while okay neighborhood of make-believe
[Music]
all the schools coming along very well
did you know that uncle Friday said we
had to have it ready tomorrow I'll say
that's true
[Music]
f x y 1 724
I brought your meals oh thank you lady
happened huh
when you called for died I thought you
sounded a little sad
Oh would you hold it while I get a straw
please sir thank you
yeah just like a couple sips now
did you hear what I said about dad
yes I did hey be CT f g JK lms o lady
ever and i just can't go to school
tomorrow
why not Daniel because I don't know
everything you don't know everything I
don't understand
well lady Lane said that we couldn't go
to school if we didn't know all the
letters and all the numbers on these
charts and I've tried and drag to learn
them like just kids I guess I can't go
and i wanted to go to school I real it
but Daniel Lady Elaine is it's just
plain wrong
you don't need to know everything before
you begin in fact that's what school is
for to help you to learn not to scare
you
how do you know Wow because i went to
school and I didn't know those things
when i started what was it like it to
school
Daniel I loved had a teacher who really
wanted to be a teacher and every morning
she would welcome us and make us feel as
though we were all going on a kind of
trip together when someone trips
something soon
sometimes we never even thought of we
learned so many things about the world
and about different countries people
ships and stars and plain and tracks
yes and trucks and cars and flowers and
about some people like some things like
other things but but what about the
letters and the numbers
oh we learned those too but that was why
we were learning that everything else
not all by themselves and did you play a
course we played teachers know that
children need to play in fact that's one
of the reasons how Elizabeth cow wanted
to have the school someplace else so
that she could have a big playground you
let have sand in it but it probably will
and what will the school be like inside
well there will be chairs that will be
just the right size for children and
young team tigers and there will be
desks it you can put milk on
ok well how you can give us milk of
course almost every school kids children
milk and time to go to the bathroom of
course you can go to the bathroom
whenever you have to it doesn't sound so
bad as Lady Elaine makes it sound I'm
just gonna go talk with her
I don't understand what should be
scaring people so much about school you
call me again if you need me Daniel I
will they be evident in the thanks a lot
[Music]
you have so many people hmm
look I can market
lady aberlin Lady Evelyn LOL see Jean
how are you I'm quite well thank you but
Anna's not the least bit happy and of
course that takes away from my own
happiness
what's wrong with him oh it's lady lane
she's got Anna all upset about the first
day of school to have a matter of fact
i'm on my way to see her right now
well she's been sayin flames to our
little Anna oh well that sounds pretty
nervous not the kind of poem she says or
what kind are they well one of them goes
like this you have to be ready you have
to be ready you have to be ready for
school for school you have to be ready
you have to be ready you have to be
ready for school
it's not you be sorry that's terrible
dr. build I think so too we've tried to
tell her i'll do my best because it's
really going to be such a nice school
well once the children find out for
themselves then things will be happier
I'll say well see later else sounds
thank you for being such a caring person
lady aberlin that's the best thing I
know anybody can be i learned a lot
about it from you
oh thank you my dear will work this
through
of course
two plus one equals three now say that
again too when equals something I don't
know why you can't get it
oh hello there a Berlin wailing oh yes
I'd like to talk with you
sorry I don't have time you all are
starting at school tomorrow and I don't
have any of these children ready now to
have children in this neighborhood we're
ready long before you started drilling
them what are you saying I'm saying that
I don't like the way you were
frightening these children you're
telling them things are just not true
two plus one equals three is most
certainly true that's right but Anna
doesn't need to know that before she
goes to her first day of school
no she needs to know much more than that
she already knows much more than that
what do you mean Anna knows that she's a
growing platipus who wants to learn and
be with other children she already knows
how to play lots of different things she
knows what she likes to eat and what her
favorite toys are what does that have to
do with school it has a lot to do with
school a lot to do with learning
I don't understand your pedagogy wanting
to learn is the most important part of
learning
I want them to read like my mom and dad
well your teacher will help you learn to
read Anna how can you learn to read
without knowing all the letters give the
teacher chance Lady Elaine incidentally
what was your first day of school like
mine
oh I had a wonderful time the teacher
had games for us to play and milk to
drink all sorts of treats and did you
know all your letters and numbers when
you got there
well not exactly did you have to know
everything
not exactly did you have a playground oh
what a fabulous playground we had I
remember I used to pretend I was an
astronaut and fly all over the place and
then when you grew up
you've got to be an astronaut
hmm do you think my playing about it had
something to do with it do you
I wonder knowing how to play well as one
of the most important things of all and
getting ready for the first day of
school
okay everyone take this green board to
Harriet tau she'll have some fine
players coming to her school tomorrow
you are good sport lady lane
I learned to be by playing come on Anna
i'll show you some really neat stuff
inside this museum
[Music]
oh you'll have plenty of time for that
when you get to school
see everyone goodbye and ponder
lots
I think I think things are better
oh I know they do but I i just had to
talk with some people here before i went
back to help them finish building
oh good i'll go over there now and help
them finish so it'll be ready for
tomorrow
Oh it'll be wonderful thanks to you
[Music]
always school bus
well lady elaine was scaring everybody
about school
do you know anybody who does that
sometimes older children will tell young
children all kinds of scary things about
school
well that's just not fair is it will
pretend about the first day of school in
the neighborhood of make-believe
tomorrow you have so many people who
care about you
we want you to like school because
there's so much you can learn that can
be so helpful to you for a long long
time I was just thinking that's one way
that i wrote my name Fred but before I
knew that I you should just write like
that just for practicing just for
pretending and also
this is another way i would show my name
show who I was
another fret and sometimes I wouldn't
feel like having a smile I just kind of
had straight like that
I always felt good when I could drop
pictures of myself just the way I was
feeling then also drop pictures of other
people that I loved think maybe I'll
leave these here and do some more
practicing on that practice bad tomorrow
use my drumsticks if and you can do the
same you know with your fingers just
make rhythms it's such a good feeling to
know you're alive with such a happy
feeling you're growing inside and when
you wake up ready to say I think I'll
make us happy new day it's such a good
feeling a very good feeling the feeling
you know that we're friends
I'll be back tomorrow hope you'll have
some good play time between now and then
you know they're people who like you
exactly as you are only one person in
the whole world like you you're special
[Music]