[Music]
it's a beautiful day in this
neighborhood
beautiful day for a neighbor would you
be mine could you be mine
it's a neighborly day in this beauty
with neighborly a4a music would you be
mine could you be mine
I have always wanted to have a neighbor
just like you
I've always wanted to live in the
neighborhood with you so let's make the
most of this beautiful day
since we're together might as well say
would you be my
[Music]
you be my neighbor
you playing
won't you please
please won't you be my neighbor
a neighbor hello to you
television friend are you I'm feeling
pretty good today I'm glad we could be
together
you see this big board that I brought in
to show you has lots of little doors on
it different material for each door
behind these doors are pictures of
people who this one is any everland
here is that graduate Clements
get this one Sharon angry
andaman degree
[Music]
Audrey cleans everything
who is that mr. McFeely this is speedy
delivery disney a lot of that
opt row we pretend that he's Bob dog
sometimes the neighborhood of
make-believe and sometimes Robert roll
[Music]
remember who was behind this this one
all these are friends
all these people are friends of mine
you know what it means a friend it means
that i know that person i know how that
person looks and what kinds of things
they do and I like to be with them
most of these friends are people that
I've helped you to know on television
do you remember who's here
speedy delivery
mr. McFeely you remember who cleans
everything
[Music]
and under remember what behind something
isn't it
now i have shown you who's behind all of
these doors here except this one now
I'll show you who's behind this
this man is a friend that I've known for
a long time
his name is buzz Wagner he has a shoe
store and he's somebody that I'd like
you to meet anyway I need to buy a pair
of shoes today
so why don't we just go to Wagner shoe
store
yes he's had a shoe store for a long
time in fact his dad and his grand that
have had that same shoe store in our
neighborhood for many years so I just
like you to see how mr. Rogers goes to
buy a pair of shoes you come with me to
Wagner shoe store
hello
[Music]
here it is
I've read are you thanks i brought my
television neighbor to see your shoes
great that's great are you missing nine
today how are you good thing I'm a
little busy right now I'm just finishing
up to my dad will be right with you
great okay thank you alright ok Dorothy
like i said i think the workout room
when you travel around the house really
like to look at cheese
here's something new since the last time
I've been here that great makes you a
little just any shoe any size and put
mine up there and just show you
different much bigger that one is than
mine so much smaller that one is think
of different people wearing these
different shoes
let's just take a look at some of the
there are some boots up here
this looks like nurses or doctors shoes
can see once
[Music]
look
you ever see people wearing shoes like
this
[Music]
neversoft soft slipper
I
take a look at some of these shoes
yourself
and try to think of some of your friends
are some of your family wearing these
different
I
this is the kind I've been looking for
see that fancy part right there that's
what i wanted for dress-up shoes I've
been trying to find them but haven't
found my own size
hi friend how are you hi how are ya good
to see you go thank you i brought my
television neighbor to see a shoe store
that but and I wondered if you had shoes
in my size like that I hope but their
friend would like to have a seat let me
check your size again you're looking
well Fred everything going ok that's
fine thanks well with you
client think you know we keep ourselves
busy in here I'm sure you do
alright we just stand on this place at
all your weight down there
no that's fine i'm gonna get the cup and
that's good
ok now that's they got the right let me
check your with her
ok that's fine you can be seated for it
thank you
okay let me check see if I have it yeah
and I share this sure you go right ahead
this is what the people used to get the
right size for your shoe and to put your
foot in like this and then they move
this around and move this around over
here but of course you do it on the
floor
this is the shoe that you selected but i
tell you i might disappoint you i don't
know if i'm going to have your proper
side like you just try it on to get an
idea if you all right it looks like and
what it feels like
ok you know it what I thought it looks
like it's just a little bit too big
What's it feel like on your footprint
that feels like I'm moving around in
there a good deal that's what I inviting
that's what I thought see it's a little
wide on your friend it's really not the
right thing for you and you're not going
to be comfortable in it like i said i'm
really not going to be able to give you
the right fit here today and the shoot
but i have a nice shoes I'd like to show
you to explain but it's nice and it
would feel better on your feet and you'd
be more comfortable right to show you
that sure would you like to walk back to
the stockroom i want to show you i would
say this is it this is where we keep all
our shoes
yeah you have a lot of them
ok right back this way friend will show
you the shoes i'm talking about this is
a stockroom her friend
it's hard to believe with all these
shoes that we have here than I really
don't have this size of the shoe that
you want but the there are so many yeah
there's an awful lot of different kind
of shoes fit one family that step right
over here Fred I'm and look for that
shoe that i was talking about i wanted
to show you here it is right here this
is this is a good-looking true friend
it's not exactly what you were asking
for but it's a good taste it's playing
simple but it's it's it's a good story
shoe and above all it would fit you
write your feet would feel better you
know that type of shoe this it has one
curve here doesn't have the two like the
fancier one here that's a marcus and
Stitch but it it would be a comfortable
shoe and above all it would be in feel
you know good in that show when it's
like a minute maybe we could try them on
seems like a sturdy she now you'll find
out better you get them on your feet how
you like them and we'll see ball if they
fit your good and it's you feel
comfortable in alright alright let's
family let's go out here and see how
they are
follow me out here and place
take one right over here Fred we're
gonna try these on you now
alright let's see how things work out
[Music]
this is this is different from this you
know this is a wingtip this is a
moccasin tip that but if it doesn't fit
there's nothing happened no no no I
don't think there's any way you want to
consider that shoe because it's just
really not the right thing for all right
we'll try this song see how this goes
look better right away just the way your
foot slid right in there huh it feels
better care better
yeah I think you'd be a lot more
comfortable and this shoot for it just
and just take a couple steps see what
they feel like when your foot maybe you
might want to look in the mirror at them
oh that feels very good yeah they they
look like they fit your right good look
for something that you can walk and be
comfortable in how but it would be like
trying both on you maybe
yeah that's a good idea to try the other
one always yet it's always good to try
the left one man to because it can be a
variances in the two feet
yeah just the way they slide in there
they look look comfortable quickly fit
your right well but as we've been
friends for a long time and you've known
what what was good for my hate
well I'm glad that you feel that way and
we try to fit you well and so far we've
done okay and who stand out for the both
of us let me see how that is it looks a
lot better not read this take off a
couple steps look in the mirror see how
they feel they are just perfect yeah
well they look they look comfortable on
your feet and i'm sure you'd be pleased
with those that are different from what
I expected but i think i'd like to wear
them back
well they must feel good if you're going
to wear them home that's right all right
well let's just put your sneakers in the
box
there's other shoes they just didn't put
your properly and you wouldn't get the
comforter and you are they
so charge right to your contract with
your place sure no problem at all happy
to do that for you
we've certainly done a lot of business
together in our lives having we sure
have over the years and I just hope we
can continue to do the same i hope we
continue to satisfy you and I just take
this in the box that I think it's gonna
be fine i'll put your receipt right
inside here for you for it
ok was a pleasure and i hope you come
back real soon
thanks again by the shirt i hope you
enjoy your shoes right bye-bye
come along
[Music]
ok
what do you think about getting new
shoes do you always get the kind you
want
I certainly didn't get the kind i had in
mind
no mr. Wagner wasn't afraid to
disappoint me by selling the shoes that
really fit me well these feel so good
and it gets fun to think about all the
different people and all the different
shoes in the world
you know what's in here don't you
my sneakers that I ward to the shoe
store
there's so many things you can do with
an empty shoe box you could pretend that
the box is a trolley and say ding ding
I don't we have some make-believe let's
make believe that some of the friends in
the neighborhood of make-believe are
trying on dress up clothes today all
right neighborhood of make-believe
point point is break and happy 2011
lovely necklace you help me with that
bowtie rubber tool that short principal
think we're always gonna be your first
thank you again and I will show up at it
it's really fun to dress up your ears
that and more
oh yeah how about this one
oh ok
oh there's another 1i want to know you
did not like it
so no no no no
oh wait wait a minute this is not fun
it's mine Robert roll from my custom box
know who had it first
oh yeah who is willing to let the other
one using marry me
ok then we'll just find another happen
if you're not willing to share
we're gonna put this and right back
where it was now then I don't care
try another you get use them whenever
you want to
well nobody's wearing
can I wear second and I get to wear
anything I want to next time
no troll troll to take off your hat and
glasses
no why should I it bothers me when you
when you two are arguing don't worry
because everything is ok now you can
give to step the Hat Robert raw you mean
you're you're willing to share
it's my turn next oh that's great
their Prince Tuesday now we can have fun
again
look I think people wear these ads to
guard kings and queens
yes really i have something i could wear
for kings and queens to some fancy
special shoes shoes what we can we see
them then show us I have to go to my
secret place
[Music]
let's go
sunday I'm hi boy they're so sparkly and
shiny
i'm glad i have these sunglasses gonna
smooth side
oh my mother lets me take them back
really everyone we're playing dress a
hub fantastic i like your header right
now lady like Anna is showing us her
special shoes
let me see them they're beautiful what
you say it's just going to put them away
come on let me see it I like some fancy
shoes myself like this
well no one's allowed to wear these
anyhow there just what i need Anna I
mean I want to dress up to know lady
Wow and what about this sharing your
supposed to share Anna yeah these shoes
what do you mean not these shoes where's
your mother and where your home but they
didn't make me share my special shoes
well I know someone who will i'm going
to call King Freddie tell him on you all
don't do that don't talking ID on a man
she's been sharing her costumes all the
less you hit with some shoes find
something else we hear what just
flattened look at it but look at when I
am NOT interested Robert all my mother
father all busy today anyway we'll see
about that
+ 16 batting your 6 and 6 plus 6 is 12
yes that's what I was afraid of sharing
a household isn't easy is it
no but I'm glad we're doing it together
absolutely my dear patty I need to speak
to you made your name fairchild I
presume
what is the reason for your visit well
it's about sharing hard we were just
talking about sharing Sarah know
anything sharing she shared a lot today
yeah and let me wear this hat and bow
tie and everything
now what is going on here what is it
lady line once and shoes she has shoes
and she doesn't even wear them shoes the
glisten and shine like jewels and gold
shoes that I later and Richard want to
wear but but there are special secrets
you
am I to understand that Anna therapist
has some very fancy shoes and Lady
Elaine thinks the shoes should be shared
you've got it toots but Lady Elaine
doesn't need them King Friday I don't
need them
I just want them silence please
fairchild you know we share in this
neighborhood
I know that that's why I came here this
is the road but there are exceptions to
the rule
Anna doesn't have to share her shoes
with you friday that's not fair i am a
fair
k be lien that don't you have anything
in your Museum go around that you don't
feel you have to share
there should be something back in there
then well not my boomerang tumor and
suing everyone knows that
yeah everyone knows that can you
understand how Anna feels perhaps a
little yeah so can you understand
well perhaps a little and is good at
sharing most things just like you
well maybe you're right i don't like
being wrong one bit but just this once I
might just be a little wrong and a
little right very good
both of you all of you come with me Lady
Elaine I have a few pocketbooks and some
gloves which I wanted to shoot you for
quite some time
I'll be back shortly buddy well the rest
of the school and it's actually think we
would thank you tuesday
I think we knew
[Music]
ok prolly a picnic body will share the
preparation and the fun
caring is hard sometimes for everyone
isn't it
everybody has some things that they
shouldn't have to share
do you have a blanket or a stuffed
animal or a pillow
well if it's extra special to you
that's something that you shouldn't have
to share that made me think I could use
this box for a bed
yeah I think I have some blankets
yes here are some blankets
a little pillow have a stuffed
yep anywhere here
I'll just show you how to make a bed
with a shoebox very simple just put
something down a little bottom like that
don't have to have a real pillow like
that you just put some material one of
your toys in another blanket over it
there you have it and if you like you
could even sing to it it's you I like
it's not the things you wear it's not
the way you do your hair but it's you I
like
the way you are right now the way down
deep inside you not the things that hide
you not your toys
they're just beside you
but it's you I like
every part of you
your skin your eyes your feelings
whether role for new i hope that you'll
remember even when you're feeling blue
that it's you I like you
it's you yourself it's you
it's you
if you have something that other
children don't have and you feel you can
share it that can really make you feel
good
it's a happy thing to share the things
you want to share
that's a part of loving it really is
it's such a good feeling to know you're
alive in such a happy feeling you're
growing inside and when you wake up
ready to say I think i'll make a snappy
today it's such a good feeling very good
feeling the feeling you know that i'll
be back when the day is new and i'll
have more ideas for you
and you'll have things you'll want to
talk about i will to the things inside
you your thoughts your feelings are all
yours and you're the one to decide if
you want to share them with anybody your
thoughts and your feelings are your own
I like sharing some of mine with you
I'll be back next time
[Music]
you always make it a special day I just
you're being yourself by
[Music]