[Music]
it's a beautiful day in this
neighborhood a beautiful day for a
neighbor would you be mine
could you be mine it's a neighborly day
in this beautiful
would neighborly day for beauty would
you be mine could give me
I have always wanted to have a neighbor
just my I've always wanted to live in a
neighborhood with him so let's make the
most of this bone folder since we're
together might as well saying what you
be mine could you be my neighbor won't
you please please won't you be my
neighbor neighbor
I'm glad we're together again could you
see what that little thing was that I
brought in with me I'll show it to you
right now it's an orange seed
looks very small doesn't
well I'll go to the kitchen and show you
what i'm going to do with this seat come
with me won't you please
things won't you be my neighbor seen
output the seat right here
what I'm going to do is to plant this
seed so I have some some soil which i
will put in the pot never planned
anything
I like to play thing guess maybe that's
enough from now the seed right there
then covered with more soil ok seed
little water
there now this seed has a chance of
growing into a tree and real oranges can
grow on that three oranges like this one
yes if you plan an orange seat you can
be sure that the tree that grows from it
will be an orange tree it would never be
an apple tree or a pear tree only an
orange tree cut this orange open so I
can show you see any seeds there
here's one that's where seeds confirmed
right in
and if you squeeze an orange get some
orange juice
[Music]
like orange juice
most people don't have orange trees of
their own because it takes a long time
for them to grow and they have to grow
in special warm parts of the world so
most people who want orange juice have
to buy it in the store
I hope that's mr. McFeely let's go see
tell you why for this it is you have it
dunno mr. feeling hungry people make
orange juice after people make orange
juice would you be able to stay and
watch it with me have a few moments
because i know you know a lot about this
come on already this is what I wanted
you to see this is a film about how
people make orange juice so let's just
put a picture picture and what oranges
grow on trees
I was just telling my friends about that
while these trees are planted together
in a grove young trees make their fruit
a little the time are those your young
trees 'as
but as they grow they produce lots of
oranges like this full-grown tree
do that to be pretty big deal
[Music]
each year watches are picked by people
who work in the Groves
but he's very good at his job
I love the smell
[Music]
you put some right in a sack and when
his sac is filled he puts the oranges
into a big wooden box called a great
[Music]
these crates are loaded onto a trailer
by a person who works a truck with a
crane on it those crates are all filled
with oranges that's right and then are
the crates taken to the juice factory
oh well not yet that comes a little
later first they have to be unloaded at
a packing house where they go
everyone that sliding board
[Music]
there's so many different shapes and
sizes are well that's right of these
people they decide which oranges should
be used for juice or for canning or sent
right to the stores
[Music]
the juice oranges are loaded onto a
truck will go to a juice factory i have
never seen so many oranges in one place
a lot of people like to drink orange
juice i'll say well here they are
arriving at the cheese factory
[Music]
get there
have to be unloaded and then washed
they set up to the juice department and
just travel a lot of looks like they're
making the final check on the oranges
before they go to the juicing machine
room is filled with those machines
that's right of each machine takes the
orange and removes the Jews they're very
fast
[Music]
that machine is squeezing the mat pass
one right after another so that's the
orange juice there isn't coming out that
too but that's that's right
freshly squeezed orange juice
now this is the machine that
concentrates the Jews forth a lot of it
can fit into a small can
you mean the kind of can that would fit
into your freezer at home
well that's right
now it's time to put the orange
concentrate into the cans
[Music]
to the lids then it's put inside a big
freezer
once it's frozen
it's checked to make sure everything is
just right
then it's sent to be packed now this
person is loading up the packing machine
and then go the cans already for the
stories where people like you and I can
go and buy them back to drink orange
juice was pretty well I do sometimes we
squeeze our own orders and sometimes we
buy it
frozen but whatever we do i like to call
it so Jay drinking your oj that's right
tricking rog I'm really glad you brought
this film
I'll take that back would you like an
orange to take with you I'd like that
come along I got one right out here
well orange for mr. mcdeere I'll eat
this along the way I have more delivery
so right now all safe delivery to you
delivery that's what you make I enjoyed
saying that about see around the
neighborhood the bye-bye mr. McFeely not
interesting
you know I wonder if the people at
brockett's bakery ever make anything
with oranges
well we go over there and see I'll just
take this orange to them come along
[Music]
thank you very much
here's your cake here's the change by
now i miss Rogers como esta usted muy
bien gracias Senor
instead the incandescent i would just
say orange in spin orange not uncommon
that I know you like origin
well I like them very much mr. mucho
what about orange juice orange juice
cool banana logo in America lets you go
to America
well there's an aeronca por usted muchas
gracias errors no IDK worst chef
Brockett he should be back in a minute
he just wanted to get some things that
we needed i see i just wondered if you
had anything here that you used oranges
are orange juice to make up as a matter
of fact we do we have orange cakes i
show you one orange cake
well that's beautiful
oranges on the top you can make it go
around either little bits of oranges in
it to ya inside we have little pieces of
oranges and also coordinator also
organized use with another hey Fred
oh hi dawn good to see you and see you
as a and I've been talking about oranges
and orange juice
excuse me for a minute thank you and
orange cakes you know me and oranges
when I was a little kid very little my
mother and dad used to give me orange
juice all the time about doing service
since I like to but here you are now
you're giving all kinds of foods too
many different people
that's right we have special new line of
health foods very healthy foods called
soy foods so if we are the things that
are made from soybeans it you want to
see them i'd like to configure you know
you really look good you know why
because I exercise and I really try to
eat healthy foods come on I'll show you
some of them now these are also a few
maybe your soy beans you need to boil
those didn't get cookin any can put
sauce over them like a tomato sauce and
just like its beginning good yeah
there's a vegetarian
that's a vegetarian burgers and it's all
vegetables no meeting that at all
and of course it's a soy food there are
soy beans that are already cooked you
just eat them then that's it
and there's tofu that's something I know
I eat a lot of tofu you like in all
different ways sharp now these are all
so drinks okay i just can't drink that
right out of there or this is something
like non-fat dry milk accepted its dry
soy milk and you put water with it and
it tastes like milk i see and hear
something that I know you like as a
matter of bag i want to give you this
one is a present
ok what is it it's a pancake and waffle
mix but it's soy flour and you can have
pancakes made out of this and maybe can
put some oranges or berries on the time
all good and it'll be all having I do
need to buy from you that need some
whole wheat bread coming up
all week what kind of flower to friend
I really like to be here all these
different foods doesn't orange cake
smell good yes it does
you know what I like to keep trying to
add new healthy foods all the time for
the things that you sell here read and
do is read their you change
thank you see there's my present enjoy
it thanks chef Brockett ok but a jury in
our neighborhood item 25 I
[Music]
ok
glad you're in our neighborhood too
let's go back to Michael
[Music]
that's a good thing stayed at that
bakery
[Music]
bread in the breadbox
do you know anybody else who puts bread
in the breadbox
when I was a little boy and I would
plant something in the ground at first I
thought it would grow very fast and I'd
be able to see something come up in just
a few minutes but as I grew very slowly
i realized that plants grow very slowly
to so little by little I learned to wait
and waiting is such an important thing
to learn to do
let's think of something to do while
we're way while we wait for something
new to do
let's try to think up a song while we're
way that's liberating and will be true
to you
let's think of something to do while
we're way too while we're way to tell
somethings through
you know it's really alright in fact
it's downright quite right to think of
something to view that specific for you
let's think of something to do while
we're waiting the fish can have their
food while they're waiting
[Music]
one thing we don't have to wait for
right now is the neighborhood of
make-believe let's do that right now
get the trolley
let's make believe that lady aberlin is
giving orange juice to her friends in
the neighborhood right ready for that
ok neighborhood of make-believe
[Music]
hi trolley would you like some orange
juice
oh that's right
trolleys don't drink
yes I have and what a fine family they
are by
horny corn flake especially well hello
there baby everything
hi honey how are you are the better for
seeing you right now you like some
orange juice
I would but I don't have any i'm sorry
but i have some for you Oh for high-end
oh my heat it looks so good
[Music]
where what it treat what did I do to
deserve that you're my neighbor and I
just thought you might like it with
thank you very much i know you work hard
oh but I like my work baby everything
making all those rocking chair yes every
time I make 1i think the people who
might sit in it and how good it might
feel for them you chairs and mighty
comfortable corny i try to make them
that way you do you make them for your
own grandchildren Oh Lady Evelyn I don't
have any grandchildren but I make them
for other people's grandchildren and
they tell me that they like them and if
they knew you they'd like you to
well I guess I'd better get back to work
would you flick that switch right there
please session that will help me inside
it and thanks again for the orange
you're welcome it's your can help a
fellow feel good
bye-bye I think I'll give some orange
Justin ladylee
[Music]
just leave it by the bell 2 i'll be back
later thanks yours truly Lady Elaine she
always seems to know that everything
minute it happens
[Music]
well this family
lady aberlin how good to see you brought
some orange juice
you mean for us to take that's right
well that's so thoughtful of you dear
want to give us just well I just thought
you might like it
and since we're neighbors somehow I
wanted us all to have something out of
the same picture a little part of the
same orange
well it's really good and so are you
lady everyone
I'll leave this one for dr. bill
whenever he wants it he's making house
costs just as I am
that's right there will take you again
you're very welcome i buy a lady a
brulee know
[Music]
cg x how are you I'm just nifty-galifty
what do you have there some orange juice
some for everybody and my part of
everybody
you most certainly are good
oh you sure make it good well it's the
oranges that grew from the trees that
make it good
oh I wish something grew on my tree
leaves growing your treat
I mean something we could eat or squeeze
you know what I mean
it looks like a big orange on your trade
surely does
[Music]
Oh exit says
our engine Graham oh well it's an orange
Graham then that's like a telegram
i just opened up and see what it says
how do i do that are you find the zipper
and then you zip it usually ships the
whole way around here and then you open
it up and read it dear cousin ex oh it's
from a cousin I guess so
oh I will come to visit you tomorrow i
want to ask you something
love your cousin Mary owl
Oh cousin Mary why haven't seen her in a
time won't be long now I would you like
to see her picture
sure yeah there's Mary picture
oh yeah i remember i'll be glad to see
her again
yes i will too I've just made up a poem
about cousins would you like to hear it
yes I was a cousin is a splendid thing
to think of all the joys they bring my
heartbeat high with sounds that saying
and songs that ring a splendid thing a
cousin
Oh access beautiful thank you for your
very welcome and thank you for the
orange juice
you welcome one another 14 cousin Mary
splendid thing would be
thank you very much very welcome here's
the photo doesn't marry spoke to break
up and i'll see you soon
cousin Mary a splendid thing
[Music]
yes becoming next time
so X the owl is excited about his cousin
Mary coming for a visit
did you notice how lady aberlin wanted
to give some of her orange juice to
everybody
it made her feel good to be able to give
each person something from her one
picture and she was really pleased when
they accepted it
I must clean up some of these things
here wash the glass and the knife
[Music]
how does it make you feel when you give
something to somebody and that person
really likes what you give the note
makes me feel good
see you next time fish
gives me a good feeling to be able to
give things to you you may not always
liked what I give you
that's all right to you don't have to
always like what people give to you but
it gives me a good feeling when I think
that you like to be with me
it's such a good feeling grew to know
you're alive and such a happy feeling
you're growing inside and when you wake
up ready to say I think I'll make us
happy new day it's such a good feeling
very good feeling the feeling you know
that i'll be back in the day is new and
i'll have more
ideas for you and you'll have things
your war to talk about i will too
half of a squeezed orange
up and under squeezed or I'll be back
next time
[Music]