it's a beautiful day in this
neighborhood
beautiful day for a neighbor would you
be mine could you be mine
it's a neighborly day in this beauty
would really pay for beauty would you be
mine could you be mine
I have always wanted to have a
neighborhood just like you
I've always wanted to live in the
neighborhood with you so let's make the
most of this since we're together might
as well say would you be more to be mine
be my neighbor you please won't you
please please won't you be my neighbor
welcome to television neighbor
this television neighborhood never seen
anything that looked like this this is
called an Otis cope
it's like a flashlight and it's
something that doctors use when they
want to take a very careful look in your
ears if I can turn it on you can see the
flesh like park that well this
particular Otis cope belongs to a
pediatrician friend of mine
do you know what a pediatrician is it's
a doctor who takes care of children when
they're ill and helps them to keep well
my friend knows how important it is to
talk about things that people might not
understand she and I both know how
people like to be told things I even
sing about it sometimes if you know that
song that I sometimes sing called I like
to be told sing it with me I like to be
told when you're going away when you're
going to come back and how long you will
stay
how long you will stay i like to be time
I like to be told if it's going to hurt
if it's going to be hard if it's not
going to hurt i like to be told i like
to be told it helps me to get ready for
all those things all those things that
are new
I trust you more and more each time that
I find those things to be true true i
like to be told because i'm trying to
grow and I'm trying to learn i'm trying
to know I like to be told i like to be
told there are many things that children
wonder about art well when you're
wondering about something you can always
ask the people you love about because
they were children once too and they
know how people like to be told all
kinds of things
well one child I know is going to have
her check up at my friends pediatric
office today and I asked if it was
alright if we came to watch and they
said it was so i'll call to see if we
can go right now
[Music]
no Jane Fred Rogers I wonder if it was
alright to come right away so Julie good
fine we'll be right over by we may go
and i'll take back the soda scope that i
borrowed come along
[Music]
hi ideal yeah and then the hi mr. Rogers
how are you I'm good how are you good
thing that i think dr. Brooks expected
ok let me just go back and check you can
have a seat thanks so much
how are you
I ok come for a family checkup
yeah you can find a story brand great
are you dr. David thinks it's good to
see you
Jean told me you'd be stopping by yes
I'm hoping to see a checkup from one of
her patients good are you leaving
yes i'm on my way to the hospital to see
some newborn babies
well they're lucky to have you for their
doc thank you very much i enjoy working
with them
how's your family doing great things
well please give them all my life will
do not hear my daughter by this way mr.
well thanks
last time I saw her nothing recently
Thank You Linda IJ well hi friend how
are you I'm fine thank you for loaning
me that you're very welcome like you to
know my television neighbor dr. breath
hi this julie yes you know Julie you're
my patient and her brother lewis and her
mother Claudia like Rogers glad to see
you julia is it alright if i watch your
checkup
thank you just wait over here
you're a fine girl okay well Julia are
you all ready for your checkup
I'm going to start by listening to your
chest with my stethoscope
sometimes it feels a little cold does it
feel cold little bit
everything sounds good now I'd like you
to take a deep breath
ah good again and once more
you did that very well ok now mister
rogers brought back the ODA scope that I
loaned him so i'm going to show him how
we use it
that's a different one there's and it's
a little different it's attached to the
wall and when I look in your ears i put
this piece on so now it's an 02 scope
and which ear would you like me to look
at first that one
ok now let's see this year that's a
healthy ear now the other year very good
to healthy eating is a little rubber
bullets
it has a tube and a little bulb and I
squeeze that when i'm looking at julies
ears so that i can tell if your eardrums
vibrate the way they should and so much
it tickles just a little doesn't it
ok thank you went okay Katrina make up
buddy when something tickle sure now I'd
like to see your mouth
remember how you open your mouth real
wide stick your tongue out and say ah
very good i'm going to use my helper
stick to help hold your tongue down
why do you say I once more good
that was wonderful okay now remember
sometimes when you look at the light
I asked you to watch the light move to
this side watch the light room over here
watch it go up down
watch you get closer and far away
very nice now i'm going to use my other
light this light is called an
ophthalmoscope and when I look in your
eyes with this light
I'd like you to look straight ahead at
the little spot on the wall the little
green spot you see that
okay look right at the green spot
ok now for the other I I like you to
look at the little picture over there
you see the picture of the sailboat
okay look at the sailboat
well I look at your eye
very good when you look in somebody's
eye doctor brick you can't tell what
they're thinking can you know I see the
back of their i called the written
oh yes now I'd like you to lie down put
your head here and your feet there your
hands at your side
are you comfortable good ok remember I
always check your tummy to see if it's
healthy
so I'm going to feel your tummy on this
side will you tell me on this side it's
a pretty healthy tell me okay now
remember every time I give you a checkup
I check under your panties to make sure
you're healthy
ok the parts we call your private parts
you remember you always keep covered up
keep your private parts clean and
covered and no one should check under
there except mommy or daddy or the
doctor
ok if anybody wants to touch you on your
panties or check on your panties you say
no until mommy okay all right now I want
to see your legs and let's see how
strong they are
oh very nice
those are healthy legs you like to run
to you you run fast walk
yeah that I get kind that they followed
that until you fall down and then
sometimes when you fall down i'll bet
you get some of these long beach don't
you wait outside can have that fun
uh-huh but they look like they're
getting better they're ok they're pretty
good now slide your legs around over the
edge like that and i'm going to get my
reflex hammer we call that the tapping
hammer remember that okay you're this is
a soft camera it's not a regular hammer
ok you feel but let's let mr. Rogers
feel that too
oh it's like rubber is squeezed key and
i'm going to tap your knees this one and
now i'm going to tap up here we watch
your fingers jump and this 10 you helped
me that time didn't you
ok just let your fingers relax while I
tap good
that-a-girl ok now I'd like to help you
down so that you can stand here in the
middle of the floor and I'd like to see
how you walk on your tippy-toes take a
few steps up on your tippy toes
oh that was very good now show me how
you walk on your heels
that's very good
now show me how you stand on one foot
the other foot hood can you hop on one
foot Julie
Wow very nice ok let's see how you grew
since the last time you had a check-up
with your two feet together in the
middle of the scale that's good let's
see how much you weigh today you've
grown since the last time you put on
another pound and a half now I want to
see how tall today you're quite a big
girl okay come on back and I'll help you
climb up we're almost done
isn't she a good climber and mackay by
she even finds on monkey bars movie more
is a good time providing god how do you
like to do that you're such a fine girl
i'm giving brittany you're right i'm
giving you 30 you're getting a swingset
pretty soon and you have a new brother
don't
yeah he's one month old and you're the
big sister I'm glad really went when you
think of coming to see dr. Breck are you
glad when you're able to come to see her
to have your check up here because you
like her huh
oh you really are baked and a healthy
young lady and yes she had a good
checkup too i'm not sure that i can i
can try it like that was pretty good
yeah i'm not sure that I can
is it all right if I sit up here and try
that see now and what did you do like
that that's fun
go like that you did it make it
yeah that's good that's a little extract
your clothes does she get to put on your
clothes
yeah he's now that your exam is all
finished and you had a good checkup
you can get dressed I think she's like
to play a little longer with you mr.
Rogers well I like you Julie I'll try
that when i get back to my place okay
glad to see you
thanks so much you get used to have you
Fred
bye-bye
thank you and your welcome to go or just
fine
good Julie is a very healthy child how
good later
[Music]
well you know Julie's been going to see
dr. Breck ever since she was a little
baby so they know each other very well
takes awhile for doctors and children to
get to know each other well and of
course Julie's mother got to be with her
the whole time and see everything that
was going on in that checkup
have you ever had a check-up like that
did any of it hurt well if a doctor has
to give you a shot
sometimes that does hurt doesn't shots
are like big pinches but the heart goes
away after a while
that's something that I know for sure
and another thing I know for sure is
that doctors can't tell what children
are thinking and feeling by looking
through their equipment or any other way
only you know what you're thinking and
feeling those are all things that you
can talk about with the people you love
it's important time well let's have some
actually
[Music]
last time we pretended that X's cousin
Mary owl had come to visit and ex had
given her a wonderful welcome
we also found that Betty Templeton and
james michael jones and adopted a little
baby girl let's make some more about all
of those people now as we pretend that
we're on our way to the neighborhood of
make-believe yes miss out i do have some
cousins
oh good of course they are all royal
course minor all elves natural LOL least
everyone I / do you presume correctly
uncle Friday you are just the person I
wanted to see next
oh well here I am do you have any
cousins
yes you see I am the daughter of
amplified his older sister Claire but my
cousins are the sons of his younger
brother Paul and of course their names
are Nikki Quentin Polly and Kevin Mickey
Quentin Polly and Kevin so you have four
cousins and Prince Tuesday makes five of
course Prince Tuesday makes five cousins
for lady aberlin that's right now why is
it that you need to know about cousins
miss out
well I'm planning a cousin reunion and
anyone who is a cousin or has a cousin
is invited to come
well that should be lovely i will play
the bass violin
well I'm just planning it right now but
i'll be back in touch with you both o
farewell there
yes farewell
uncle Friday yes isn't it exciting about
the new Jones maybe oh yes the adopted
baby dog
oh it's not a baby doll or not the kind
you find in a store
no no this is a real adopted baby
oh well of course then that's very
exciting i'm going to south with now to
see her again
I just love being close to that little
family i shall send you a gift for the
baby
how kind of you uncle Friday let me
think now what would that little girl
baby and joy
yeah I know I'll be right back under
that you're 50-something something it
feels good here is a picture for that
little gray reads a picture of a real
king
maybe I could even give her a royal kiss
for you
oh well yes if that seems appropriate
well it is appropriate uncle Friday
babies love to be loved and then you may
offer a royal kiss along with the
picture
thank you see you later farewell needs
to be idea sending the picture
Oh doctor bills in southwood maybe I'll
see him there
don't you think she's the loveliest baby
you ever start dr. Beale she's a
beautiful child you must be very proud
of her
all we found it very difficult to sleep
last night dr. bill or was the baby
crying oh no it was just that we were so
excited and we wanted everything to be
just right
well I can understand that bill bill
well you know this little baby's coming
has made your father jeans
oh I know oh yes isn't it wonderful
sometimes i wonder if i'll be a good
mother my will every mother of wonders
about that but how can you be a good
mother dr. Beale or just by being
yourself and asking for help when you
need it
well yes I should remember that after
all I do braised Johnny
hi everybody has the baby why she's a
very healthy week girl i'm just
finishing my examination
I'm glad to be her pediatrician did you
with the baby's name is Lady a know what
are you going to name would you like to
tell her Betty also i will James we
thought of the name together
why don't we just say it together it's
fun musical anyone the whole world could
say it together
I can hardly wait to hear our baby's
name
he's carrying templeton jones carrie
dell coconut Templeton Joan she's named
for the members of his family
James family and my family it's a long
name but we're all going to call her
Carrie Dale oh I think that's just
wonderful and carrie dell i bring you
something from King Friday 1300 that's
the first i've heard her talk
well you can tell King Friday that his
picture made an impression her he sent
her something else to someone else but
King Friday sitting beside his picture a
royal kiss
[Music]
well go for neighbors we have we have I
need to get back to my neighborhood
office
thank you very much for your kind
attention from dr. VLAN make an Adele
grow into a bill bill healthy woman and
now as you can call me uncle ki hope
that's a wonderful idea
in fact don't think that everything is
wonderful and that baby of yours can
tell already how you love her Betty
Oh dr. Beale you make a mother feels so
good
that's the kind of thing you could have
told me Betty now a goodbye to you all
and here's a platipus kiss to go along
with the Royal when Katie Dale well dr.
bill I'm going to stay and visit here
when i'll tell your uncle and goodbye
everyone
[Music]
[Applause]
oh how she's a lovely baby its kitty del
oka knock templeton jones heresy i'm
going to tell King Friday how much he
liked this picture and his kiss telling
Carrie dello connect templeton jones i
guess everyone will call her Carrie Dale
and someday she'll know that that's her
very own name of course the most
important thing about her is that so
many people love her already
somewhere deep inside of her she must
know that and that's the most important
thing for a baby to know I guess it's
the most important thing for anybody to
know that people can love us just the
way we are
[Music]
you are my friend you are special
you are my friend you're special to be
you are the only one like you like you
my friend I like you in the day in the
nighttime anytime that you feels the
right time for a friendship with me
you see in our I and the expression you
are my friend
you're special to me there's only one in
this wonderful world are special i hope
you're learning to love people besides
your mom and dad friends are very
important when children are growing up
in fact friends are very important all
through our lives no matter who you are
you are certainly somebody that people
can love it's such a good be linked to
know you're alive
it's such a happy you're growing inside
and when you wake up ready to send
I think I'll make us happy
it's such a good feeling a very good the
feeling you know that i'll be back when
the day is and i'll have more ideas and
we'll have things you'll want to talk
about i will to always make each day
such a special day you know how by just
your being yourself
there's only one person in this whole
world like you people can like you
exactly as you are back
[Music]