[Music]
it's a beautiful day and this
neighborhood
beautiful day for a neighborhood
would you be mine
good
it's a neighborly day in this one with
the neighborly day for a beauty
what you
tutoring mine i have always wanted to
have a neighbor just like
I've always wanted to live in the
neighborhood with you
let's make the most of this beautiful
day since we together might as well say
you be my be mine you be my neighbor to
please please please won't you be my
neighbor
we're neighbors again I'm glad to be
with you want to show you something
really pretty
mr. McFeely loan this snow globe to me
so I could show it to you when you go
like this it looks like it's snowing
inside take a real close look at it not
beautiful
you could even pretend that you're in
here where it's snowing
pretend you're upside down and you're
right side up is that knocking your
pretend or is it right here in my place
it's here let's see who's at the door
oh it's mr. McFeely speedy delivery
speeding globe delivery 0 found another
one for you to show
oh thank you i was just showing the this
is an even bigger one
well it works just the same up turn it
over yeah and its nose inside inside the
club i think these are beautiful mr.
Wickfield you can keep them as long as
you like really sold by the way I have a
videotape i found i thought that you and
your neighbor may like to see it
what is it for it's called how people
make serious cereal
yeah i know a lot of people who like
cereal so I find this interesting
certainly would you have time to show it
to I'd be glad to see it again
and while we're watching it I'll explain
it to you very good picture picture
writing up with this down carefully with
the other one to snow globes and you say
we can we can borrow them for a walk for
a while now there's the tape okay how
people make cereal box right here take a
look on picture-picture and how people
make cereal
that's a good idea was to make really
when people make cereal they start with
a mixture of flour salt and other
ingredients
that's within the big bag this man uses
a special crane to move the bag over to
watch a Gannett container with all the
hot
but what happens next in a moment he's
going to can open the bottom of the bag
so that the ingredients can pour out
into the hopper was gonna cut that you
know he's gonna grag outcomes that must
make a lot of serious but surely does
[Music]
now from the hopper the mixture travels
through some pipes and into the sifter
sifter
what does a sifter do sometimes the
ingredients get lumpy sister shakes out
the lump so that the mixture is smooth
almost like sand and everything gets
stirred up some more in this machine
[Music]
like he's checking carefully that's
exactly what he's doing and now onto the
cooker
here's where the water is added to the
dry ingredients
oh so it's like Joe exactly and the
dough then moved to this part of the
booker where it gets shaped in the
circles it's only a Syrian people that's
works that's more traveling through
pipes this woman check some of the 0 to
be sure the shapes are just right
she also squeezes the dough to make sure
that it's just right to squeeze squeeze
[Music]
and here we are at the drying drying
machine yes trying helps make the serial
crunchy
[Music]
and after its dried and pumped
the serial is checked by this man he
smells it and carefully looks at it
dispatch seems to be just fine morning
along there and there they go the dance
single serial gets to these bins
its measured so exactly the right amount
goes into each package when the bin Phil
double the serial is emptied into this
machine where to put it all back the
open end of each bag is sealed up tight
so that the serial won't come out app
that conveyor belts right this bag of
cereal join lots of other bags of cereal
that's how people make au shaped cereal
Oh
rats cereal mr. materially oh that's
really interesting like you thought you
enjoyed this one of my favorite tapes
you know Betsy night supposed to babysit
so at lambs later on that lamp at lambs
so if you like come on over
oh I'd be glad to come over and I'll
bring the snow globes with me when I can
tell there's no hurry we're not in a
hurry for keeping for a few days just
bring yourself all right thank you very
much for your generous delivery guy like
my work as a matter of fact if there's
any thank you
what if there's anything you need
Billy's the lorry brings it to you here
with pd sr CD deliveries are sweetie
the little room speedy delivery to you
and to everybody
thank you delivery go see you around the
neighborhood all right mr. failing but I
and you're welcome the speedy delivery
is a speedy delivery
speedy delivery too
beautiful have an idea
it's going to require a trip to the
kitchen this idea
[Music]
but this is castle
trolley
the fact draw the tree
[Music]
the museum go around
platipus mound who lives in the clock
daniel tiger
now let's make believe that something
happens around the Platypus place and
around Daniel's clock which gets
everybody wondering
remember it's just pretend