Oh
it's a beautiful day in the neighborhood
ok for a neighborhood would you be mine
could you be mine
it's a neighborly day in this week you
would neighborly day for beauty would
you be mine could you be mine
I have always wanted to have a neighbor
just like you
I've always wanted to live in the
neighborhood with you so let's make the
most of this whole day since we're
together we might as well say would you
be mine could you be mine
be my neighborhood won't you please
won't you please linds won't you be my
neighbor
hello neighbor welcome to this
neighborhood
do you have any idea what I might have
in this bag i'm going to show you it's a
puzzle you imagine what might fit in
there right up here it says greetings
that's a royal word for hello
let's take all of this to the kitchen
and put it to go
ok now does that look like Queen Sara
where do you think she fits
no oh there and what about Prince
Tuesday juicy there who's this King
Friday the 13th he fits to do things
like puzzles
it's important to look and listen with
your eyes your hands and your ears if
you will look carefully listen carefully
you will find a lot of things carefully
look
and listen
it's good to look carefully listen
carefully
that's the way you learn a lot of things
carefully look and some things you see
are confusing some things you hear are
strange but if you ask someone to
explain one or two you'll begin to
notice a change in you care
all the listen carefully
that's a way to keep on growing
carefully look look and listen
now we're the king the prince and the
Queen live in the castle in the
neighborhood of make-believe let's just
get the castle
and with the castle there
and the factory tree and lives in the
tree and who lives in the museum go
around playing Fairchild
platipus mound and Daniel's clock
and the trolley now we've been
pretending that X the owl is giving
flying lessons to anyone who wants them
but last time
Lady Elaine said she was going to teach
people to fly because she had a hat with
a propeller on it so let's think more
about that as the trolley goes into the
neighborhood of make-believe oh I'm not
doing well at all trolley
well I've tried everything excess told
me to do like jump and collins bread and
cheer and nothing works i guess i'll
just give up
thanks trolley
oh it's no use that hear you say
something cousin I just said it's no use
what's discouraging you well i thought i
could learn to fly
you mean by yourself yes I was taking
lessons with ex he knows how to fly well
but he's a bird align with strong Prince
that's right you know tuesday i think
that we should have a picnic and talk
about some things
well I don't feel like a picnic well I
do and i'll just go to the kitchen and
bring some things and if you're here
when I get back we can eat together
we'll see peanut butter and jelly
oh well see you
butter and jelly won't do it
what do you mean you thought you and
healing sure and I can teach you to fly
high in a minute in a minute
yes now you just take this and put it on
and you will fly how you what is it
magic magic you just put it on and when
you put it on you go somewhere close
your eyes and fly high to its hole
thanks auntie Lydia way this sounds much
easier the next is flying lessons you is
easy does it work for you
sort of but remember it's pretend
I can really believe it i'm finally
going to fly
alright propellers on wow ready get the
careful Tut's be careful that's what
everybody says
be very careful I've got to get back to
my museum or I go
[Music]
oh word people out here who
oh well I guess I'll have to have my
picnic alone outs
oh that I hear all right out
sounds like tuesday
oh boy
tuesday what happened to you how I fell
down from where from a Blair and uncle
Freddy come to the castle garden every
night with you as usual uncle Friday you
prepared to pick more ready to this
phone down
Oh son are you all right there
oh my arm hurts a little bit father I
will find dr. bill immediately imagine
what is this hat you're wearing
someone told me it would help me fly
high and you fell for that poor d out
your arm
yes it really hurt them for lady aberlin
thanks miss politican oh hello yes right
away will bring it as soon as we can
Thank You uncle Friday that was writing
he says the doctor bill wants us to
bring tuesday to the hospital right away
and to do it very carefully i'll be glad
to know thanks
you call to mother of course there
well
this what he did just tried to fly and
went down like that
he was probably thinking wow with this
hat on i'll just buy all over the
neighborhood but that's not the way it
works now now he has to go to the
hospital when his dad heard that he had
fallen his dad said I'm going to call
the doctor right away
when they found out that he had to go to
the hospital he said we my mom come with
me and she said of course they all went
off to the hospital
nothing like magic hats can make a
person fly have to be so careful it's
just birds and bats and bees and
airplanes and things like that that fly
not people
well we'll pretend more about this
neighborhood of make-believe next time
healing Fairchild I don't think she
meant any harm
probably got those that's could help
people fly
let's give the fish some food
fish are hungry very hungry and very
beautiful i love the way they move see
fish don't have to fly to move
beautifully gracefully through the water
think that's the phone
ya lo Maxine
oh yes I'm glad to hear from you
certainly would be
yeah well I'd like to show my neighbors
something before we come
alright good thanks very much for by
that was Maxine wrote choose a friend of
mine she's part of a string quartet i'd
like to show you pictures of stringed
instruments that she and her friends
play them in here somewhere
yep here this this is our musical
instruments book
now you know a quartet means there are
four
here the string quartet there to
violence and the viola which is a little
bigger and a cello which is the biggest
of all and these are the four
instruments in the Uptown string quartet
that's the name of my friends group
well let's just go see the real
instruments and the four friends who
play them
let's visit the Uptown string quartet
come along
[Music]
here we are let's just go on
cake
Maxie thanks I'd like you know my
television neighbor Eileen Maxine lisa
and i am the Uptown string quartet what
was that you all were playing when I
walked in we were playing uh Scott
Joplin's rag I would feel like dancing
the whole way down
I like it too I'd like my friend to hear
how the yet different instruments sound
how the violin sound higher than the
viola and the viola sounds higher than
the cello can do that
okay all right place kale
[Music]
hmm
you all love playing together dekhi yes
yes do you have anything that that you
play that have that you can hear the
separate instruments as a matter of fact
we do we have a piece that actually I
start off and i think i will start it
off and the other instruments coming
separately you start it i started i see
the pieces cool vibes vibes and so I'll
thought
[Music]
nice together then I jump in after they
finish I jump in with a soul figure
[Music]
it sounds like somebody talking on a
couple would you do that one
[Music]
thanks
then do you play in this one yes I play
the bass line and I play it with my
fingers put sacado at flex experience
Oh fucking it yes up the well I'd love
to hear all that together okay with it
so you know your vibes
[Music]
thank you everyone always liked making
music I mean even when you were little
girls absolutely absolutely
yeah well music was always in my house
when I was growing up and I was inspired
to take piano lessons it because my
uncle taught me how to play the
boogie-woogie and then then when I got
to be eight years old I got to not only
just play the piano by myself but I got
to play with friends i get to play the
violin with my buddies
alright so what did you play well I used
to love a tune entitled lightly row
[Music]
that reminds me of when I was little and
I used to like to pick up my friend my
friend has a name my instrument and his
name is baby love you mean your violin
is called baby laughs baby love i named
him baby love because I love him and
he's like a baby a little baby to me
that I can caress and hold whenever I
want to and I would pick up baby love
sometimes in play
however I felt sometimes I I feel happy
and sometimes I feel sad and I could
play all those feelings and emotions on
my instrument if I if I if I felt sad i
would play something like this
[Music]
you're happy too
maybe next scene has a happy sound well
I your feelings remind me of when I was
a little girl and I sit next to my
grandmother and at the piano she was a
pianist I come from a very musical
family and uncle played trumpet and sax
but my favorite thing was listed with my
grandmother and she would play a song
for me and one of the song she told me
was twinkle twinkle little star
so when I play it I think of my
grandmother
sing it to me with a twinkle in her eye
was I remember you must be mighty
special for you to have that inside
yeah I'll always have mine really i
remember being inspired by a lot of
musicians my my teachers and my parents
took me to see woodwind quintet sand big
bands and string quartets I can still
see those musicians on stage in my mind
and my father used to always play the
piano and I and he used to really swing
and so sometimes now I can play in my
cello and that reminds me of those
experiences that all reminds you when
you were a little girl you carry all of
that with you
yeah i know you have a lot of rehearsing
to do so I better be on my way
well don't go just yet mr. Rogers we
have something very special for you
we're going to play one of your
compositions entitled you are special
and we've done a very special
arrangement of this for you all I'd like
to hear that
oh it and not any of you going to use
the boat
no we're all going to pluck the strings
i put the candle and makes this
arrangement very great
I'm listening
[Music]
you always make it a beautiful day in
this neighborhood and you are very
special you uptown string quartet and
proud to be your neighbor see I
rehearsed little one with yeah yeah okay
[Music]
one back
aren't they wonderful
even when they were little they loved
music
I really like them our friends at the
uptown string quartet
that puzzle that I brought with me
what's in the kitchen is
[Music]
Prince Tuesday Queen Sara
in the daytime in the night-time anytime
that you feels the right time for a
friendship with me
you see F R I e and d special you are my
friend
you're special to me one in this
wonderful world you alone special i was
just thinking when you like somebody you
want to share the things that you like
with that person I guess that's why I
want to share so much with you
will do more together next time
we surely will it's such a good feeling
to know you're alive it's such a happy
feeling you're growing inside and when
you wake up ready to say I think sound
like a snappy it's such a good feeling a
very good feeling the feeling you know
that i'll be back when the day is new
and i'll have more I for you and you'll
have things you'll want to talk about
we always have things to talk about
don't we and things to do together
I look forward to our times together you
make each day such a special day
you know how by just your being yourself
right there's only one person in this
whole world like
people can like you exactly as you are
I'll be back next time bye
[Music]
Oh
it's a beautiful day in the neighborhood
beautiful day for a neighbor would you
be mine could you be mine
it's a neighborly day in this week he
would neighborly day for beauty would
you be mine could you be mine
I have always wanted to have a neighbor
just like you
I've always wanted to live in the
neighborhood with you so let's make the
most of this whole day since we're
together we might as well say would you
be mine could you be mine more be my
neighborhood
won't you please won't you please plans
won't you be my neighbor
hello neighbor welcome to this
neighborhood
do you have any idea what I might have
in this bag i'm going to show you it's a
puzzle you imagine what might fit in
there right up here it says greetings
that's a royal word for hello
let's take all of this to the kitchen
and put it to go
ok now does that look like Queen Sara
where do you think she fits in there and
what about Prince Tuesday
Juicy's there who's this King Friday the
13th he fits to do things like puzzles
it's important to look and listen with
your eyes your hands and your ears if
you will look carefully listen carefully
you will find a lot of things carefully
look
and listen
it's good to look carefully listen
carefully
that's the way you learn a lot of things
carefully look and some things you see
are confusing some things you hear are
strange but if you ask someone to
explain one or two you'll begin to
notice a change in you care ollie
listen carefully that's a way to keep on
growing air fully booked
look and listen
now we're the king the prince and the
Queen live in the castle in the
neighborhood of make-believe let's just
get the castle
put the castle there
and the factory
[Music]
the tree and lives in the tree and who
lives in the museum go around playing
Fairchild
platipus mound and Daniel's clock
and the trolley now we've been
pretending that X the owl is giving
flying lessons to anyone who wants them
but last time
Lady Elaine said she was going to teach
people to fly because she had a hat with
a propeller on it so let's think more
about that as the trolley goes into the
neighborhood of make-believe oh I'm not
doing well at all trolley
well I've tried everything excess told
me to do like jump and collins bread and
cheer and nothing works i guess i'll
just give up
thanks trolley
oh it's no use that hear you say
something cousin I just said it's no use
what's discouraging you well I thought
he could learn to fly
you mean by yourself yes I'm just taking
lessons with ex he knows how to fly well
but he's a bird align with strong prunes
that's right you know tuesday i think
that we should have a picnic and talk
about some things
well I don't feel like a picnic well I
do and i'll just go to the kitchen and
bring some things and if you're here
when I get back we can eat together
we'll see peanut butter and jelly
oh well see you
butter and jelly won't do it
what do you mean you thought you and he
were dealing sure and I can teach you to
fly high in a minute in a minute
yes you just take this and put it on and
you will fly how you what is it magic
magic you just put it on and when you
put it on you go somewhere close your
eyes and fly high to its hold thanks
aunty Lee away and this sounds much
easier the next is flying lesson is easy
does it work for you
sort of but remember it's pretend
I can really believe it i'm finally
going to fly
alright propellers on wow ready get the
careful Tut's be careful that's what
everybody says
be very careful I've got to get back to
my museum for I
[Music]
o people out here
oh well I guess I'll have to have my
picnic alone outs
oh that I here all right
oh sounds like tuesday
oh boy tuesday what happened to you how
I fell down from where from a Blair and
uncle fatty come to the castle guard
night with you as usual uncle Friday you
prepared to pick more ready to this
phone down
Oh son are you all right there
oh my arm hurts a little bit father I
will find dr. bill immediately imagine
what is this hat you're wearing
someone told me it would help me fly
high and you fell for that poor d out
your arm
yes it really hurt elephant for lady
aberlin thanks miss politican oh hello
yes right away will bring it as soon as
we can
Thank You uncle Friday that was writing
he says the doctor bill wants us to
bring tuesday to the hospital right away
and to do it very carefully i'll be glad
to know thanks
you come to mother of course dear back
with you
well
this what he did just tried to fly and
went down like that and he was probably
thinking wow with this hat on i'll just
buy all over the neighborhood but that's
not the way it works now now he has to
go to the hospital when his dad heard
that he had fallen his dad said I'm
going to call the doctor right away
when they found out that he had to go to
the hospital he said we my mom come with
me and she said of course they all went
off to the hospital
nothing like magic hats can make a
person fly have to be so careful it's
just birds and bats and bees and
airplanes and things like that that fly
not people
well we'll pretend more about this
neighborhood of make-believe next time
healing Fairchild I don't think she
meant any harm
probably about those that's could help
people fly
let's give the fish some food
fish are hungry very hungry and very
beautiful i love the way they move see
fish don't have to fly to move
beautifully gracefully through the water
think that's the phone hello Maxine
oh yes I'm glad to hear from you
certainly would be
yeah well I'd like to show my neighbors
something before we come
alright good thanks very much for by
that was Maxine wrote choose a friend of
mine she's part of a string quartet i'd
like to show you pictures of stringed
instruments that her friends play them
in here somewhere
yep here this this is our musical
instruments book
now you know a quartet means there are
four
here the string quartet there to
violence and the viola which is a little
bigger and a cello which is the biggest
of all and these are the four
instruments in the Uptown string quartet
that's the name of my friends group
well let's just go see the real
instruments and the four friends who
play them
let's visit the Uptown string quartet
come along
[Music]
here we are let's just go on
cake mixing thanks I'd like you know my
television neighbor Eileen Maxine Lisa
and Diane the Uptown string quartet what
was that you all were playing when I
walked in we were playing uh Scott
Joplin's rag I would feel like dancing
the whole way down
I like it too I'd like my friends to
hear how the yet different instruments
sound how the violin sound higher than
the viola and the viola sounds higher
than the cello can do that
ok alright let's scale
[Music]
hmm
you all love playing together dekhi yes
yes do you have anything that that you
play that have that you can hear the
separate instruments as a matter of fact
we do we have a piece that actually I
start off and i think i will start it
off and the other instruments coming
separately you started i started i see
the pieces cool vibes vibes so I'll
thought
join me
tomorrow
[Music]
that nice together then I jump in after
they finish I jump in with a soul figure
[Music]
it sounds like somebody talking on the
couple would you do that one
[Music]
thanks
then do you play in this one yes i play
my bass line and I play it with my
fingers put sacado at plex exclaims oh
fucking Yes Doctor Who i'd love to hear
all that together
ok sorry your vibes
[Music]
ok