it's a beautiful day in this
neighborhood
beautiful day for labor would you be
mine could you be mine
it's a neighborly day and good
neighbourly a4a beauty would you be mine
would I have always wanted to have a
neighborhood just like oh I've always
wanted to live in the neighborhood with
you so let's make the most of this six
were together we might as well say
you'll be mine you be my neighbor want
to play please won't you be my neighbor
neighbor you ever sing
won't you be my neighbor while I sing it
please won't you be on you my
neighborhood you know learning things
like songs and new words and thinking
about neighbors and friends are always
of growing growing inside and part of
the fun of that kind of growing is that
it can go on all our lives now before we
do anything else I want to go get
something to show you home right out
here
now if you'll just wait here a few
seconds I'll be right back
it'll be a little like peekaboo but i'll
be going to get something this is a cat
whose name is Jimmy and he's a friend of
mine you find booming yes such a fine
cat and the beautiful big cat look
oh please don't leave
he wants to go under there
come on Jimmy yeah I want my television
friends to see oh my you're so heavy i
remember when Jimmy was just a kitten in
fact I remember his visiting me right
here in this place and my showing him to
my television neighbors i think i like
to think about that time when you were
just a little kitten
yeah just a little kitten
are you like it there do you like to sit
there on the floor
someday you're going to be a big cat
like your mom like your dad there's
somebody at the door
well let's go see who's at the door it's
concedes at the door
oh it's mr. McFeely just really good day
to you is this a good time to pick up
it's a perfect time mr. McFeely Jimmy
some very frisky Kitty well I'll take
good care of them and there you will
fear rather neighborhood all right mr.
really thanks so much you're welcome
without my Jimmy was little then and now
he has grown to be a big cat the big
caddy is today he was born a kitten and
then grew an igloo when he grew and grew
and he grew and now he can do what a
kitten couldn't do his story is his
history
he's grown to be a very graceful cat
still pretty frisky em and everything
that he's done is part of his history
just like everything about you is all
part of your history you were born a
little baby
and you grew to be able to do the things
that you do now
do you know any little babies I brought
a book of pictures of babies and
children you want to go over there he
seems to want to go over that way i'll
show you this this is a book of babies
and little children some neighbors of
ours
I'd like you to see
I
Oh
and to think everybody was a baby once
all human beings start out being babies
I wonder if you ever think about the
things that you can do now that you
couldn't do when you were a little baby
can you feed yourself now can you go to
the potty by yourself now can you say
some special words can you wait for a
while for something you want a lot
those are all things that babies can't
do those things show how much your
growing see who that is
oh it's mr. McFeely Oh mr. McFeely they
do you know it's not often that I have a
delivery and a pickup at the same place
well i know you have a pickup because
I've got we can you wait just
second-guess you
Jimmy's over here already made your
Jimmy is your pick up but i don't think
i have any delivery but I have a
delivery for use a deliberate war
well i don't think i ordered any flowers
mr. i know you didn't but Betsy and I
are giving flowers all of our best
customers this week will thank you for
that that is just beautiful and so I
don't let me don't let me take Jimmy
from you there
he's a fine can't it certainly is you
know a nice ideas that all part of your
advertising campaign all part of the
campaign and we grew the flowers
ourselves so we could give them away
well they're very nice and I thank you
for them you're quite like oh by the way
how's the bean plant coming along
haven't checked it today but i will when
you have these flowers look at until the
plant grows I certainly do and I thank
you for that
speedy delivery to you design right
Jimmy I you find cattle take it back to
his family
we've all ground haven't we serve you
know you and I bye-bye
they're beautiful flowers to think the
McFeely screw those and would give them
to us when I was little and I gave some
flowers to somebody flowers that I found
like dandelions or daisies or weeds I
would just cram them into a glass and
give them i didn't know anything about
how to arrange flowers so that they
would look fancy but I always gave my
flowers with love and of course that's
the best arrangement for anything
McFeely obviously give there's with left
to just put those there and let's check
to see how the bean plant is doing
takes time to grow doesn't it will give
it some mist takes time and a lot of
patience but there are lots of things we
can do while we're waiting for growing
just the neighborhood of make-believe
factory what's this museum go around
Daniel's clock platters mound
that's a surprise x and Henrietta Street
there now last time we pretended that
the people and animals of the
neighborhood of make-believe were
concerned because there was some big
thing rolling from westwood toward where
they live
when she heard about it lady elaine
fairchilde thought she'd call Purple
Panda to see if anyone on the planet
purple knew anything about it
among other things let's make believe
that purple panda comes for a visit
right from Planet purple and what do you
suppose that big thing will look like
you think will be as big as a chair or a
table or a sink or a refrigerator
k trolley will think about those things
and the neighborhood of make-believe
of course it's a purple light emergency
you don't think I'd call for nothing do
you
now it's purple panda there yes and
thanks
is that you purple panda well I need you
here and make believe as soon as you can
come
well that was fast purple way right you
are now what is the emergency
there's a big thing that's rolling here
from westwood and I thought you might be
able to help us with it
what kind of big thing is it nobody
knows at least I haven't seen it is it
purple
oh I forgot to ask they said it was
around so I thought you know something
about it after all you're from around
planet
excuse me lady lane oh hi neighbor aber
low you know Purple Panda don't know yes
of course
hello Purple Panda LOL I've come to warn
everybody that the big thing is almost
here
what do you think will happen i don't
know in westwood all it did was roll
right through what color is it
you'll soon see shall we go to the
castle you bet your life
I'm ready mayor Maggie I presumed
correct as usual King Friday have you a
report on the big I do it's just about
to arrive in this neighborhood from
which direction
oh I don't see
Oh coming here we are
hey it's only purple and welcome purple
bender
Thank You King Friday everybody's been
thinking you're some scary big thing
look everyone it's just our friendly
purple and i am not a scary big thinking
friday of course you are not to know I
am
but what is that huge round mass rolling
in over there
now that's a different story
see what they maintain its call out the
true
excuse me confront even that big thing
didn't do any harm in westwood couldn't
just wait and see what happens here on
one condition
what is that that you and marry Maggie
and purple panda speak to the big thing
and see what it plans to do your troops
at your service sire you may guard the
castle but hold your fire our
representatives will speak to the big
thing very good sire intermediate
delegation proceed
I'm outta here
hello big thing you are no longer in
westwood you have rolled into the
neighborhood of make-believe are you
planning to roll on out
King Friday the 13th who lives over in
that castle has called the Royal troops
out and considers using force but we
were hoping that wouldn't be necessary
we're really peace-loving people around
here and as mayor of westwood I'd like
you to know that I'm certainly grateful
that you passed us by
and maybe you will pass us by two
I wonder what that means I'll go tell
King Friday what will you tell him I'll
tell him that the big thing kind of
teeter-totters keep talking peace and
passing on that seems to get the most
response we will
Oh daddy I just heard the big thing is
here
what are we going to do when you're
negotiating right now son
yes I wish I could help if I were great
big Ida neighbor aber I presume
correct as usual King Friday your report
we seem to be making some progress sire
would you like some forest golden no no
not yet but thanks for backing you up
all the way you are impressive troops
i'll help to mr. aber thanks Prince
Tuesday pieces the word very good
neighbor as soon as we mentioned peace
and passing on and things like that
the big thing kind of teeter-totter as
if it were happy or something was nice
looks very hopeful there is growth in
this situation I really do think so I
mean if we can talk and think and feel
peace
we'll all be the better for it feel
thank you yes darling the word draws the
word word what do you suppose that big
thing really is
looks like a big wall matter or a nagger
a beam or something to me
well we can pretend it to be anything we
want you suppose it was little one time
and grew to be that big or dispose it
started out being do you like to make up
stories about little things that grow
big
well I want play a game with I'd like
you to take a good look at all of these
places in the neighborhood of
make-believe and then I'm going to take
one of them away and see what if you can
guess which 1i take away all right not
purple panda i'll just put him back here
you ready and don't look I'm going to
take one away
all right now you can look
which one did I take away oh the tree
let's do it once more I'm gonna take one
other way you ready
now look who
oh is that the castle that's gone right
ok now i have to put these all away as
after you play with things you put them
back
ok the museum go around the mound and
the clock if I can take the full of once
there it's time to feed the fish
there you are fish they look hungry all
colors of fish all sizes Fisher like
people and that they grow little by
little inside and outside so they can
become big fish the way children grow
little by little inside and outside so
they can get to be grown up
I want to show you this book you know I
showed you the baby and the children's
pictures earlier now I want to show you
that those babies and children grew up
to be adults this baby grew up to be
this woman
this baby boy grew up to be this man
this little girl grew up to be this
woman this boy grew up to be this man
and this boy grew up to be this man and
this girl grew up to be this woman this
boy grew up to be this man all neighbors
hear this girl who grew up to be this
woman you see children can grow to be
adults outside and inside you used to
creep and crawl
well but then you learn to walk real
well there was a time you too and cry
but then you learn to talk and my you
almost always dry you almost always do
your best
I like the way you're growing up it's
fun that's all you're growing
you're growing you're growing in and
you're growing you're growing you're
growing all about your hands are getting
bigger now your arms and legs are longer
now you even sense your insides grow
when mom and dad refuse you
so you're learning how to wait now it's
great to hope and wait somehow i like
the way you're growing up it's fun
that's all
someday you'll be a grown-up too and
have some children grow up to then you
can love them in and out and tell them
stories all about the times when you
were there sighs the times when move
found great surprise in growing up and
it's fun
that's all you are growing
your girl you're growing in and you're
growing
growing your grow
somebody at the door we're growing
people here or the court even want to
come in
glad to see you through to see you and
this is my television neighbor this is
uniform and anger con
last time we were here when I was a baby
she certainly wasn't much she's grown
what you come on in
you've got a book with you yes you just
at the library
would you read the book for me are you
reading you
yes we just learned learning to read
this year let me blame when fish too
and here is one fish and here are two
fish and this one is brad is a red one
and this is nothing is a blue on to the
next page breakfast blue fish
Oh a spear fish is black this way is a
little Sun where is that little staff
meeting and what about this one this one
has a width talk on say what a lot of
fish down on long wished i have a lot of
fish in my place to you know that I take
care
no the virtual what about this some
thing and some set aside one has and
that woman is patent it doesn't really
happen the fury
uh-huh it's fun to read silly things to
hear from here to there
funny things are everywhere
you sure are you are some who like to
run then once you find a hat so oh my oh
me oh my what a lot of funny things go
by what a lot of funny things go by
thank you for showing us that money yo
Malcolm you certainly read very well do
you like to read
yes you do I bet you've read to her
avenue suite right to really meet every
day and we like to go to the library to
borrow books that's wonderful
well I'm mighty glad to have you for
neighbors I just remember when you were
a tiny baby thank you for going to show
us that and you read to me i hope you'll
come again thank you i thought by my
dear you can learn through reading all
of your life
thanks you guys bye-bye una
have wonderful neighbors gives me a good
feeling you know to know that people are
really enjoying their reading and
they're growing it's such a good link to
know you're alive in such a happy
feeling you're growing inside and when
you wake up ready to say I think out
make sure it's such a good feeling very
good feeling the feeling you know that
i'll be back when the day is new and
i'll have more ideas for you and you'll
have things you'll want to talk about I
will too
you always make each day a special day
you know how I gesture being you sure
you may have some pictures of yourself
as a baby or as a young person you save
those pictures because they'll be a day
when you get grown up then you'll want
to look back and see how much you've
grown
outside inside
I'll be back next time bye-bye